Guide to the North Star Mining Company and Associated Records
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Rocky Bar Gold Mining Company, Series IX; 3
  - EXECUTIVE RECORDS
    - Agreements, claims, deeds
      - Indenture, 1863 (Box 90, Folder 1903)
      - Agreements, 1891, 1893 (Box 90, Folder 1904-06)
    - Special Reports and Projects
      - Field notes and survey of mine, 1871 May 22 (Box 90, Folder 1907)
      - History of the Rocky Bar, post-1929 (Box 90, Folder 1908)
    - Stock documents
      - Ledger, 1864-91 (Box 90b, Folder 1909)
      - Day book
        - Cash book, p. 1-27, 1863-66 (Box 90c, Folder 1910)
        - Cash book, p. 278-280, 1881-83 (Box 90c, Folder 1910)
        - Assessments, p. 30-79, 1879-86 (Box 90c, Folder 1910)
      - Certificates (mostly blank), 1878-93 (Box 90, Folder 1911)
  - OPERATION RECORDS
    - Map of the Rocky Bar mine, 1865 Jan 12 (Box 90, Folder 1912)
  - FINANCIAL RECORDS
    - Day book (journal), 1864-84 (Box 90e, Folder 1913)
    - Accounts, 1864-66,1870-77
      See: Stock ledger, p. 31-32, 111-207, Box 90, folder 1909
- Tribute Mining Company, 1877-96; Series X; 1.25
  Tribute was eventually taken over by North Star in 1896 and information on the mine after that date can be found in the North Star records (Series VIII).
  - EXECUTIVE RECORDS
    - Incorporation, By-Laws, Minutes
      - By-laws, 1879 (Box 90, Folder 1914)
      - Minutes of directors/stockholders meetings, 1879-96 (Box 90, Folder 1915)
      - Copies of minutes and material from meetings, 1896 Jun 26 (Box 90, Folder 1916)
    - Correspondence
      - Correspondence (resignations and transfer of company), 1896 (Box 90, Folder 1917)
    - Stock documents
      - Ledger, 1877-96 (Box 90g, Folder 1918)
      - Transfer journal, 1879-95 (Box 90h, Folder 1919)
      - Certificates (mostly blank), 1879-96 (Box 90i, Folder 1920)
      - Certificates, 1896 Mar 23 (Box 90, Folder 1921)
  - ORE AND BULLION RECORDS
    - Ore records, Jan (Box 90, Folder 1922)
- Other Mining Companies and Associations, 1853-1925; Series XI; 3
  The companies are arranged alphabetically and material within each group follows the organization used throughout the collection. Four of the groups are from areas other than Nevada County and this information has been noted. Unidentified mining records are placed at the end of this series.
  - A. CHAVANNE & CO. QUARTZ MINE
    This company took over the Mount Hope Company (Series XI) in 1858 and eventually became known as the Rocky Bar Company (Series IX).
    - Agreements, claims, deeds, 1853-59 (Box 90, Folder 1923)
      See also: Brennan's letter which was found with these documents, Box 91 folder 1961A.
  - ADAMS HILL CONSOLIDATED MINING COMPANY
    - Receipts for stock certificate tax, 1879-81 (Box 90, Folder 1924)
    - Receipts for stock certificate tax, 1884 (Box 90, Folder 1925)
  - AMELIA GOLD MINING COMPANY
    - Bank book (F. Berton & Co.), 1880-81 (Box 90, Folder 1926)
  - AMERICAN POWDER PACKING COMPANY
    - Statements of issues of stock, 1892 (Box 90, Folder 1927)
    - Receipt for stock certificate tax, 1896 Apr 1 (Box 90, Folder 1928)
  - BADGER HILL COMPANY
    - Agreements, claims, deeds, 1858 May 4 (Box 90, Folder 1929)
  - BENJAMIN FRANKLIN CLAIM
    - Agreements, claims, deeds, 1859 Oct 8 (Box 90, Folder 1930)
  - CALIFORNIA MINING COMPANY
    - Agreements, claims, deeds, 1901 Apr 29 (Box 90, Folder 1931)
  - CENTRAL NORTH STAR MINING COMPANY
    This company was probably absorbed by the North Star sometime in the 1890s and information on the mine in the twentieth century can be found in the North Star records (Series VIII).
    - Agreements, claims, deeds, 1894, 1899 (Box 90, Folder 1932-34)
  - CHAMPION MINES
    The Champion mines were taken over by North Star in 1911 and information on the mine after that date can be found in the North Star records (Series VIII).
    - Agreement, Champion to J. M. O'Brien, selling properties to North Star, 1911 (Box 90, Folder 1935)
    - Austin Walrath vs. Champion (US Circuit Court): Brief of appellee, 1895 Oct (Box 90, Folder 1936)
    - Report on the Champion group of mines by John Ross, Jr., 1908 Jul 5 (Box 90, Folder 1937)
    - Champion mines production 1893-1910 (Box 90, Folder 1938)
    - [Financial ledger], 1892-93 (Box 90j, Folder 1938A)
      Unclear if all the records in this volume refer to the Champion Mines
    - Receipts from North Star for development work in Champion mines, 1911 (Box 90, Folder 1939)
  - CINCINNATI GOLD MINING COMPANY
    - Copy of records claiming Cincinnati Hill Quartz Mine, 1910 Apr 23 (Box 90, Folder 1940)
    - Copy of records claiming Cincinnati Hill Quartz Mine, 1910 Apr 23 (Box bsd, folder 1940A)
  - CONSOLIDATED MINING COMPANY
    - Agreements, claims, deeds, 1875 Jan (Box 90, Folder 1941)
  - EDMONTON LEDGE ORE COMPANY
    Formerly known as the Morse & Currier claim.
    - Agreements, claims, deeds, 1864-65 (Box 90, Folder 1942)
    - Agreements, claims, deeds, 1867 (Box 90, Folder 1943)
  - EMMET CONSOLIDATED MINING COMPANY
    - Receipt for stock certificate tax, 1878 (Box 90, Folder 1944)
    - Receipt for stock certificate tax, 1882, 1884 (Box 90, Folder 1945)
  - FRANCIS RANCH
    - Agreements, claims, deeds, 1855 Feb 8 (Box 90, Folder 1946)
  - GIANT GOLD MINING COMPANY
    - Photographs by Ed. E. Johnson
      - Middle Tunnel, Giant Mine (albumen), ca. 1860-1920
        See: Oversize, Box 94, folder 2137
      - Sierra Buttes--[Looking East] (albumen), ca. 1860-1920
        See: Oversize, Box 94, folder 2138
  - GRASS VALLEY CALIFORNIA GOLD EXTRACTING COMPANY
    - Prospectus, stock certificate, mining claim (Box 90, Folder 1947)
  - HAMBURG MINING COMPANY
    - Receipts for stock certificate tax, 1878-82 (Box 91, Folder 1948)
    - Receipt for stock certificate tax, 1884 (Box 91, Folder 1949)
  - HAWPATCH COMPANY
    - Agreements, claims, deeds, 1866, 1873 (Box 91, Folder 1950)
  - HUESTON HILL QUARTZ LODE
    - Agreements, claims, deeds, 1863 May 1 (Box 91, Folder 1951)
  - IDAHO - MARYLAND QUARTZ MINE
    - Map
      See: Oversize, Box 113, folder 2367
  - INDEPENDENCE GOLD MINING COMPANY
    - Checks and bank account, 1911-12 (Box 91, Folder 1952)
  - LUCK-NOW CLAIM
    - Agreements, claims, deeds, 1858 Jun 19 (Box 91, Folder 1953)
  - MAGENTA CONSOLIDATED GOLD MINING COMPANY
    This company was probably taken over by the North Star in 1894 and information on the mine after that date can be found in the North Star records (Series VIII).
    - Statements of issues of stock, 1892 (Box 91, Folder 1954)
    - Proxy, 1890 May 14 (Box 91, Folder 1955)
    - Receipts for stock certificate tax, 1891-94 (Box 91, Folder 1956)
  - MAMMOTH SILVER MINING COMPANY
    - Receipts for stock certificate tax, 1878-79 (Box 91, Folder 1957)
  - MARYSVILLE AND NEVADA POWER AND WATER COMPANY
    Marysville, located in Yuba County, is adjacent to Nevada County.
    - Map of pipeline, 1908 Dec 10 (Box bsd, folder 1957A)
  - MINE WORKERS PROTECTION LEAGUE
    See also: North Star special reports section, Box 44 folder 1006
    - Letter from trial commissioners charging W. E. Maxwell with defrauding the league (Box 91, Folder 1958)
  - MINT GOLD AND SILVER MINING COMPANY
    - Receipts for stock certificate tax, 1878-79 (Box 91, Folder 1959)
  - MORTIMER MINING COMPANY
    - Receipts for stock certificate tax, 1878 (Box 91, Folder 1960)
    - Receipts for stock certificate tax, 1882, 1884 (Box 91, Folder 1961)
  - MOUNT HOPE COMPANY
    This company ran the Rocky Bar mine (Series IX) from 1856-58, and was then taken over by the A. Chavanne & Co. (Series XI) which later became the Rocky Bar Mining Company (Series IX).
    - Copy of letter by superintendent Michael [Brennan] on his death, 1858 Feb 21, ca. 1858 Feb (Box 91, Folder 1961A)
  - MURPHY MINING COMPANY
    This company operated mines in Ophir Canon, Nye County, Nevada.
    - Minutes of directors/stockholders meetings, 1873 Jul 17 (Box 91, Folder 1962)
    - Letter to James D. Hague, 1871 Aug 1 (Box 91, Folder 1963)
    - Agreements, claims, deeds, 1871, 1873 (Box 91, Folder 1964)
    - Receipts, 1870-71 (Box 91, Folder 1965)
  - NEW VERDE MINES COMPANY
    This company succeeded the Empire Star Mines Company Ltd. (Series II) and seems to be one of the last mining corporations of Grass Valley.
    - Flyer advertising sale of mining and mill equipment of Pennsylvania Mine, Zeibright Mine, North Star Mine, Murchie Mine, Empire Mine, 1958 Sep (Box 91, Folder 1966)
    - Inventory, [1958] (Box 91, Folder 1967)
  - OMAHA CONSOLIDATED GOLD MINING COMPANY
    - Correspondence, 1890
      See: Gold Hill letters received at San Francisco, Box 4, folder 73-74.
    - Agreements, claims, deeds, 1892 Apr 9
      See: Oversize Box 94, folder 2138
    - Drafts used to purchase Gold Hill stock, 1890 Jun (Box 91, Folder 1968)
    - Receipt, 1878 Dec 21 (Box 91, Folder 1969)
  - ORIGINAL EMPIRE MILL AND MINING COMPANY
    Sometime after 1897, this company became known as Empire Mines and Investment Company (Series I).
    - Letter, 1883 Dec 21 (Box 91, Folder 1970)
    - Insurance policy, 1896 Feb 1
      See: Oversize, Box 113, folder 2368
    - Description of lands conveyed in deeds, William B. Bourn to Empire, 1879 Sep (Box 91, Folder 1971)
    - Statements of issues of stock, 1892 (Box 91, Folder 1972)
    - Proxies, 1890 (Box 91, Folder 1973)
    - Receipts for stock certificate tax, 1878-80 (Box 91, Folder 1974)
    - Receipts for stock certificate tax, 1882 (Box 91, Folder 1975)
    - Receipts for stock certificate tax, 1884-85 (Box 91, Folder 1976)
    - Receipts for stock certificate tax, 1889 (Box 91, Folder 1977)
    - Receipts for stock certificate tax, 1892-94 (Box 91, Folder 1978)
    - Water accounts
      See: Series V, Box 22, folder 543.
  - ORIGINAL HIDDEN TREASURE MINING COMPANY
    - Correspondence, 1885-86
      See: North Star Correspondence, Received at San Francisco, Boxes 30-31, folders 749-61
    - Receipts for stock certificate tax, 1878-81 (Box 91, Folder 1979)
    - Receipts for stock certificate tax, 1884, 1887 (Box 91, Folder 1980)
  - PIONEER REDUCTION WORKS OR COMPANY
    - Bullion slips and assay certificates, 1895-97 (Box 91, Folder 1981-2003)
    - Bullion slips and assay certificates, 1897-99 (Box 92, Folder 2004-21)
    - Bullion slips and assay certificates, 1904 (Box 92, Folder 2022-29)
    - Bullion slips and assay certificates, 1906-08 (Box 92, Folder 2030-46)
  - PITTSBURGH MINING COMPANY OR CLAIMS
    - Agreements, claims, deeds, 1873 Jan 25 (Box 92, Folder 2047)
    - Simon Novitzky vs. Robert McCook, David McCook, 1875 Feb (Box 92, Folder 2048)
  - PLACER CREEK MINE
    - Agreements, claims, deeds, 1874 Nov 13 (Box 92, Folder 2049)
  - PRIMROSE VALLEY RANCHE
    - Agreements, claims, deeds, 1856 Jan 26 (Box 92, Folder 2050)
  - PROVIDENCE GOLD MINING COMPANY
    - Ore assays, 1898-99 (Box 92a-92b, Folder 2051-52)
  - RIVER MINES COMPANY
    - Agreements, claims, deeds, 1919 Apr 29 (Box 92, Folder 2053)
  - ROGERS QUARTZ MILL
    - Agreements, claims, deeds, 1891 Sep 18 (Box 92, Folder 2054)
  - SCADDEN FLAT GOLD MINING COMPANY
    The Scadden Flat mine was taken over by North Star in 1895 and information on the mine after that date can be found in the North Star records (Series VIII).
    - Scadden Flat vs. Elizabeth Scadden (California Supreme Court), 1897 Oct (Box 92, Folder 2055)
    - Stock certificates, 1895 Aug (Box 92, Folder 2056)
  - SHAMROCK COMPANY
    - Agreements, claims, deeds, 1865 Jan 25 (Box 92, Folder 2057)
  - STOCKBRIDGE QUARTZ MINING COMPANY
    The Stockbridge mines were taken over by North Star in 1894 and information on the mine after that date can be found in the North Star records (Series VIII).
    - Agreements, claims, deeds, 1861-68 (Box 92, Folder 2058-65)
      See also: Oversize, Box 94, folder 2140
    - Agreements, claims, deeds, 1876 (Box 92, Folder 2066)
  - [SUUM CUIGUE] CLAIM
    - Agreements, claims, deeds, 1898 Sep 7 (Box 93, Folder 2067)
  - TWIN RIVER CONSOLIDATED MINING COMPANY (NEVADA)
    This company operated mines near Twin River, Nevada, which is probably in Nye County.
    - Certificate of incorporation, 1872 Jul 3
      See: Oversize, Box 119, folder 2401
    - Correspondence, 1871 (Box 93, Folder 2068)
    - Agreements, claims, deeds, 1873-74 (Box 93, Folder 2069-71)
  - TWIN RIVER MINING DISTRICT ([NYE COUNTY], NEVADA)
    - By-laws (two copies), 1864 Aug 1 (Box 93, Folder 2072)
    - Amended laws (two copies), 1864 Sep 1 (Box 93, Folder 2073)
    - Certificates and field notes of land surveys in Nye County, 1865 Sep (Box 93, Folder 2074)
  - WARD BEECHER CONSOLIDATED MILL & MINING COMPANY
    - Receipts for stock certificate tax, 1878-81 (Box 93, Folder 2075)
  - WASHINGTON MINING COMPANY
    - Stock certificate, 1879 Sep 4 (Box 93, Folder 2076)
    - Receipt, 1881 Oct 25 (Box 93, Folder 2077)
  - WESTERN GRAVEL MINE
    - Agreements, claims, deeds, 1874 Oct 13 (Box 93, Folder 2078)
  - WESTERN MINES CONSOLIDATED
    - Correspondence, 1928 (Box 93, Folder 2079)
    - Writ of attachment, 1925 Jun 27 (Box 93, Folder 2080)
  - WHITE & SHILOH MINING COMPANY
    - Miscellaneous papers, n.d. (Box 93, Folder 2081)
  - WOLF CREEK QUARTZ MINING COMPANY
    - Stock certificates (blank), ca. 1891 (Box 93, Folder 2082)
  - YAQUI-PROVIDENCIA MINING COMPANY
    This company was incorporated in Arizona and worked mines in Mexico.
    - Agreements, claims, deeds, 1907, 1909 (Box 93, Folder 2083-84)
  - UNIDENTIFIED MINING RECORDS
    - Executive Records
      - Correspondence, Charles W. Kitts to J. H. Hammond, 1889 (Box 93, Folder 2085)
      - Correspondence, L. Gilson to Charles E. Johnson, 1892 (Box 93, Folder 2086)
      - Agreements, claims, deeds, 1857 (Box 93, Folder 2087)
      - Agreements, claims, deeds, 1860-66 (Box 93, Folder 2088)
      - Agreements, claims, deeds, 1864-65 (Box 93, Folder 2089-90)
      - Agreements, claims, deeds, 1876 (Box 93, Folder 2091)
      - Agreements, claims, deeds, 1882, 1889 (Box 93, Folder 2092-93)
      - Agreements, claims, deeds, 1899 (Box 93, Folder 2094)
      - Accident records, p. 179-207, 1913-20 (Box 93a, Folder 2095)
      - Legal notes, ca. 1890 (Box 93, Folder 2096)
      - Stock assessment certificates, 1885 Sep (Box 93, Folder 2097)
    - Operation Records
      - Annual report, n.d. (Box 93, Folder 2098)
      - Mines samples and mapped by Joy, 1931-32
        See: Oversize, Box 119, folder 2402
      - Map of Grass Valley - Nevada City mining claims and mills, 1867
        See: Oversize, Box 119, folder 2403
      - Map of Grass Valley - Nevada City mining claims and mills, 1899-1900 (Box 93, Folder 2099)
      - Maps of Grass Valley - Nevada City mining claims, 1930, n.d.
        See: Oversize, Box 113, folder 2369
    - Ore and Bullion Records
      - Memorandum of bullion, 1887 Apr 28 (Box 93, Folder 2100)
      - Assay records, p. 3-160, 1899-1900
        See: Box 93, folder 2095
      - Notes on processing, n.d. (Box 93, Folder 2101)
      - Printed form, receipt for James J. Ott assay office, ca. 186- (Box 93, Folder 2102)
    - Financial Records
      - Ledger, 1890-91 (Box 93b, Folder 2103)
      - Cash book, 1878-81 (Box 93c, Folder 2104)
      - Miscellaneous accounts, 1868-71 (Box 93, Folder 2105)
    - Pay Roll Records
      - Time book, 1898-1903 (Box 93, Folder 2106)
    - Other Material
      - Photographs
        - Mine buildings (albumen), 1892
          See: Oversize Box 113, folder 2370
        - Mine buildings, 1990 (Box 93, Folder 2106A)
        - Miner at worker, 1990 (Box 93, Folder 2107)
        - Negatives for prints in folders 2106-07, ca. 1940 (Box 93, Folder 2108)
        - Miners and machinery (albumen)
          See: Oversize Box 94, folder 2141
- Printed Material, Series XII; 0.5
  The material consists primarily of printed pieces about mining or Grass Valley found among the corporate records. The series is chronologically arranged.
  - New Year's Song, 1876 as sung by Ned Barry, at Buckley's Varieties (describes San Francisco) (Box 93, Folder 2109)
  - Grass Valley Daily Union, 1890 May 9
    See: Oversize, Box 119, folder 2404
  - "The Stewart Mining Bill," Mining and Scientific Press, 1893 Feb 11 (Box 93, Folder 2110)
  - Nevada County Promotion Committee. Nevada County California., 1902 (Box 93, Folder 2111)
  - "Englebright for Congress," Transcript Print (Nevada City, California), 1908 Oct 7 (Box 93, Folder 2112)
  - "The Gold Ores of Grass Valley, California" by Ernest Howe, Economic Geology. vol. XIX no. 7, 1927 Nov 7 (Box 93, Folder 2113)
  - Drama of the Comstock by Paul Smith (Virginia City, Nevada), 1949
    See: Oversize, Box 119, folder 2405
  - "Brief History of Columbia," Mother Lode Magazine ", ca. 1950 (Box 93, Folder 2114)
  - Desert, 1951 Dec (Box 93, Folder 2115)
  - California Dept. of Natural Resources, Division of Mines. Mineral Information Service. vol. 6 no. 4, 1953 Apr 1 (Box 93, Folder 2116)
  - The Arizona Republic, 1953 Jun 28
    See: Oversize Box 119, folder 2406
  - The Union (Grass Valley - Nevada City, California), 1954, 1962
    - May 1, 1954 issue contains history of Empire and North Star.
      See: Oversize, Box 119, folders 2407-08
  - "1860--Pony Express Centennial--1960." Virginia City Times (Virginia City, Nevada)
    See: Oversize Box 113, folder 2371.
    The issue contains a story on the Savage Mine, Virginia City, Nevada, which is documented in the collection Savage Mining Company and Associated Records, WA MSS S-1318
  - American Gold News (San Andreas, California), 1961
    See: Oversize, Box 113, folder 2372
  - Grass Valley Historical Museum, 1961 (Box 93, Folder 2117)
  - The Cathedral of the Hills The First Methodist Church, 1962 (Box 93, Folder 2118)
  - Printed form, "Preliminary Report upon the_________Quartz Mine, n.d. (Box 93, Folder 2119)
  - Maggie Hutchinson's essay on Sugar Loaf Mountain, Nevada County, n.d. (Box 93, Folder 2120)
  - Blotters advertising insurance companies and typewriters (Box 93, Folder 2121)
  - Miscellaneous papers, n.d. (Box 93, Folder 2122)
- Oversize, 17.5
  Oversize, contains oversize material from Series I-XII. The arrangement is based on the size of the material but also parallels the order of the collection.
  - SERIES II. EMPIRE STAR MINES COMPANY LTD.
    - Other Material
      - Design for book cover, Gold: The Story of the Empire Star Mines, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 2123)
  - SERIES III. GOLD HILL MINING COMPANY
    - Executive Records
      - Correspondence - Received at San Francisco, 1890,96-97 (Box 94, Folder 2124)
      - Stock documents - Sale of delinquent stock, 1895 Dec 4 (Box 94, Folder 2125)
    - Ore and Bullion Records
      - Memoranda of bullion, 1902-03 (Box 94, Folder 2126)
  - SERIES IV. GRANITE HILL MINING & DEVELOPMENT CO.
    - Executive Records
      - Agreements, claims, deeds - Agreements, indentures, instruments, 1898 (Box 94, Folder 2127)
  - SERIES VI. MASSACHUSETTS HILL MINING COMPANY
    - Executive Records
      - Stock documents - Certificates (blank), n.d. (Box 94, Folder 2128)
  - SERIES VIII. NORTH STAR MINING COMPANY
    - Executive Records
      - Correspondence - Sent by Grass Valley, 1898 Jul 15 (Box 94, Folder 2129)
    - Financial Records
      - Annual statement, 1888 (Box 94, Folder 2130)
      - Annual statements, 1890-95 (Box 94, Folder 2131-36)
  - SERIES XI. OTHER MINING COMPANIES AND ASSOCIATIONS
    - Giant Gold Mining Company
      - Photoprints by Ed. E. Johnson - Middle Tunnel, Giant Mine (albumen), ca. 1860-1920 (Box 94, Folder 2137)
      - Photoprints by Ed. E. Johnson - Sierra Buttes--[Looking East] (Box 94, Folder 2138)
        - (albumen), ca. 1860-1920
    - Omaha Consolidated Gold Mining Company
      - Agreements, claims, deeds, 1892 Apr 9 (Box 94, Folder 2139)
    - Stockbridge Quartz Mining Company
      - Agreements, claims, deeds, 1865 Nov 14 (Box 94, Folder 2140)
    - Unidentified Mining Records
      - Other material
        - Photoprints - Miners and machinery (albumen) (Box 94, Folder 2141)
  - SERIES III. GOLD HILL MINING COMPANY
    - Operation Records
      - Maps and diagrams (Box 95, Folder 2142)
    - Financial Records
      - Superintendent's statements and drafts, 1890-91 (Box 95, Folder 2143-50)
      - Superintendent's statements and drafts, 1893 (Box 95, Folder 2151)
      - Superintendent's statements and drafts, 1895-97 (Box 95, Folder 2152-64)
      - Superintendent's statements and drafts, 1898-1900 (Box 96, Folder 2165-95)
      - Superintendent's statements and drafts, 1901-03 (Box 97, Folder 2196-2223)
  - SERIES IV. GRANITE HILL MINING & DEVELOPMENT CO.
    - Executive Records
      - Court actions - John J. Ryan vs. Granite Hill (California Superior Court), 1894-95 (Box 98, Folder 2224)
  - SERIES V. GRASS VALLEY WATER COMPANY
    - Executive Records
      - Stock documents - List of stockholders, 1891 May (Box 98, Folder 2225)
    - Financial Records
      - Copy of ledger postings, 1885-92 (Box 98, Folder 2226)
  - SERIES VII. NEW YORK HILL MINING COMPANY
    - Executive Records
      - Stock documents - List of stockholders, 1885-90 (Box 98, Folder 2227-32)
      - Stock documents - List of stockholders, 1892 (Box 98, Folder 2233)
      - Stock documents - List of stockholders, n.d. (Box 98, Folder 2234)
    - Financial Records
      - Statements of receipts and disbursements, 1885-87 (Box 98, Folder 2235-47)
      - Paid vouchers, 1888-93 (Box 98, Folder 2248)
  - SERIES VIII. NORTH STAR MINING COMPANY
    - Executive Records
      - Incorporation, By-Laws, Minutes - Copies of minutes and material from meetings, 1885-86 (Box 99, Folder 2249-50)
      - Incorporation, By-Laws, Minutes - Copies of minutes and material from meetings, 1888-90 (Box 99, Folder 2251-53)
      - Incorporation, By-Laws, Minutes - Copies of minutes and material from meetings (Box 99, Folder 2254)
      - Correspondence - Received at Grass Valley, 1912 (Box 99, Folder 2255)
      - Insurance - Policies, 1884-85 (Box 99, Folder 2256-57)
      - Insurance - Policies, 1887-88 (Box 99, Folder 2258-62)
      - Insurance - Policies, 1889-91 (Box 100, Folder 2263-71)
      - Insurance - Policies, 1892-94 (Box 101, Folder 2272-80)
      - Insurance - Policies, 1895-97 (Box 102, Folder 2281-87)
      - Insurance - Policies, 1897-99 (Box 103, Folder 2288-96)
      - Insurance - Policies, 1915 (Box 103, Folder 2297)
      - Special Reports and Projects
        - Reilly, Wright property (Oro Flat Mine) 1893 Mar 8 (Box 104, Folder 2298)
        - Massachusetts Hill properties, 1893 Oct 27 (Box 104, Folder 2299)
        - Hoisting engine, ca. 1900 (Box 104, Folder 2300)
      - Stock documents
        - List of stockholders, 1896 (Box 104, Folder 2301)
        - Sale of delinquent stock, 1879, 1885 (Box 104, Folder 2302)
    - Ore and Bullion Records
      - Ore and waste records - Paper documents, 1886-96 (Box 104, Folder 2303-13)
      - Massachusetts Hill ore delivered to North Star mill reports, 1896 (Box 105, Folder 2314)
      - Summary of ore records, 1889 (Box 105, Folder 2315)
    - Financial Records
      - Monthly statements, 1885-87 (Box 105, Folder 2316-18)
      - Monthly statements, 1893-94 (Box 105, Folder 2319-22)
      - Monthly statements, 1895-97 (Box 106, Folder 2323-27)
      - Monthly statements, 1898-99 (Box 107, Folder 2328-29)
  - SERIES VIII. NORTH STAR MINING COMPANY
    - Financial Records
      - Tabulated statements
        - Summaries, 1888-97 (Box 107, Folder 2330-31)
        - Tabulated statements of superintendent's monthly account, 1890-92 (Box 107, Folder 2332-34)
        - Tabulated statements of superintendent's, 1893-99, n.d. (Box 107, Folder 2335-43)
      - Analyzed statements
        - Monthly analyzed statements of disbursements - Paper documents, 1888, 1891 (Box 108, Folder 2344-45)
        - Monthly analyzed statements of disbursements - Paper documents, 1892-94 (Box 109, Folder 2346-51)